Phalen Hazel

pchaze@yahoo.com ● 7117-808-1137 ● Lancaster, Pennsylvania

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/phalen-hazel/ ● GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/PhalenH
Portfolio">https://ghalenh.github.io/phalen-portfolio/

Physical Therapist Assistant pursuing a career change into the Information Technology (IT) field as a hard-working Full-Stack Web Developer. Developed a secret santa manager website, Maze game web app, and a tech related blog site. I'm passionate about turning ideas into results through precise code, creative designs, and fluid user interactions and experiences. Completed the Upenn LPS coding bootcamp with certification.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap

Backend: NodeJS, Express, MySQL, Handlebars, OOP, ORM, MVC

Projects

Wishlist: Secret Santa Manager

https://github.com/PhalenH/gift-exchange-manager | https://wishlistmanager.herokuapp.com/

- All around contributor (front-end and back-end)
- Manage your work, family, or friend holiday gift exchanges all in one place.
- The website allows easy event detail customization, set reminders for events, and provides access to setting your personal wishlist. I contributed to front-end/back-end connection, server setup, handlebars, models, front-end javascript and helper functions, and helped with styling
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, Handlebars, CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, Node-cron

The Maze Runner

https://github.com/PhalenH/MazeGen | https://isaacicarnes.github.io/MazeGen/

- All around contributor (front-end)
- A basic maze game where a user traverses a series of mazes as fast as possible.
- A mobile responsive maze game to play against friends, for fun to stay busy, and can work as memory training. Personal contributions included landing page and highscore page setup, styling, and javascript functions as well as local storage setup and character movement.
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, UiKit, Giphy API, ACNH API

Tech Blog

https://github.com/PhalenH/tech-blog | https://afternoon-everglades-02639.herokuapp.com/

- Sole contributor to application
- Community blog site where users can create and read tech related blog posts.

- Uses CRUD operations to allow users to create/delete/edit posts of their own as well as read and leave comments on other user's posts
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, Handlebars, CSS, HTML

Work Experience

Neffsville Nursing and Rehabilitation Physical Therapy Assistant

June 2019-Present Lancaster, Pennsylvania

- Provide high quality Physical Therapy services for residents, caregivers and the facility
- Implementing effective and diverse treatment programs appropriate for adult and geriatric rehabilitation residents with diagnosis ranging from joint replacements, neurological disorders, fractures, and amputations among others
- Participate in specific data collection to analyze and assess safest and most productive services
- Achieved highest average productivity rate across our therapy department (PT, OT, ST) for over 2
 years.

Spooky Nook Sports Convention Services

November 2015-August 2019 Lancaster, Pennsylvania

- Worked with a variety of clients on events which ranged from corporate meetings, weddings, and black tie events as well as others with event numbers ranging from 10 to 1000+ people
- Supplied audio and visual setup for events, computer/laptop assistance, and any tech based problems clients would encounter
- Provided efficient IT assistance and resolutions to problems during event while coordinating with clients and other employees to provide high quality service

Cooper-Booth Wholesale Warehouse employee

June 2015-September 2015 Lancaster, Pennsylvania

- Worked 10+ hour days focused on maximum efficiency of selecting and packing items
- Daily problem solving to improve effective working environment and work around item supply issues
- Helped train new employees as needed

Education

Central Penn College

Summerdale, PA Graduated May 2018 March 2019

Associates in Applied Science- Physical Therapy Assistant Licensed Physical Therapy Assistant

- Cumulative GPA: 3.8
- Activities: Physical Therapy club, Vice-President of club during final semester

University of Pennsylvania, College of Liberal and Professional Studies Remote Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate Expected Graduation February 2022

- Completed Bootcamp focused on front-end and back-end web developments
- Coding Languages learned: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, NodeJS, Express, MySQL, Handlebars, OOP, ORM, MVC

Additional Skills

- Completed FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design course (9 modules)
- Experience working with external REST APIs in additional to designing custom REST APIs with MysSQL
- Experience working in Node.js and creating small backend databases
- Strong written and verbal communications skills
- Detail oriented with quality time management skills
- Strong work ethic and a positive attitude
- Experience working with team to organize, plan, and execute best possible work thanks to strong interpersonal and leadership skills